A Guide to the Andrew Jackson Montague Papers, 1854-1938
Library of Virginia
- X: Printed Materials, 1842-1937., Extent: 14. (Box 48-61)
  - A Connotary: Definitions not Found in Dictionaries by John Garland Pollard (autographed), 1933. (Box 60, Folder 19)
  - A song written by Milton Lusk to encourage the repeal of Prohibition, [1933]. (Box 60, Folder 20)
  - A bill to repeal certain specific Acts of Congress and an amendment thereto enacted to regulate the manufacture, sale, or possession of intoxicating liquors in the Indian Territory, now part of the State of Oklahoma, H.R. 6219, Seventy-third Congress, second session, 3 January 1934. (Box 60, Folder 21)
  - Mattaponi River, Va.: Letter from the Chief of Engineers, United States Army, Seventy-third Congress, second session, 15 June 1934. (Box 60, Folder 22)
  - Preliminary Survey of Rural Electrification in Virginia for State Corporation Commission by Allen J. Saville and Associates, 1 March 1935. (Box 60, Folder 23)
  - Shooting High Dance Revue Presented by the Chapman Schools of Dance,23 May 1936. (Box 60, Folder 24)
  - Southern Progress, volume XLVII, number 1, July 1936. (Box 60, Folder 25)
  - Congressman Andrew Jackson Montague: The People's Choice (2 copies), 4 August 1936. (Box 60, Folder 26)
  - The Right Man on the Job! cartoon from the Richmond Times-Dispatch of 6 August 1928 (2 copies), reprinted 4 August 1936. (Box 60, Folder 27)
  - The Democratic Register: Congression Yearbook, 1936. (Box 60, Folder 28)
  - Envelope from the House of Representatives, Committee of the Judiciary, with note that it had contained clippings for Montague's 1936 reelection bid, [1936]. (Box 60, Folder 29)
  - Independent Journal of Columbia University, volume 4, number 10, 2 April 1937. (Box 60, Folder 30)
  - Memorial Building & Endowment Fund Home for Needy Confederate Women, stationary (3 sheets). (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - The Powers of Men by William James. (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Overweight: Its Cause and Treatment by Horace John Howk and Haynes Harold Fellows. (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Advertisement for Knox Gelatine. (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Envelope with printed War Department and handwritten note Childrens Letters, Family Letters. (Box 61, Folder 5)
  - Reorder reminder from Artcraft. (Box 61, Folder 6)
  - Lifetime guarantee for Sheaffer's Lifetime Pen. (Box 61, Folder 7)
  - Advertisement for Whelan's, the Woman's Specialty Shop. (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - Quotes and comments on the Constitution from Tom Watson's Magazine. (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Camay soap wrapper. (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - How to Save the Corporation by Peter S. Grosscup. (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Empty photograph cover from Otto Sarony Co. Studios. (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Advertisement for La Mers Studio, New York, New York. (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Unto us a child is born; unto us a son is given. (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Blank checks (2 checks). (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Virginia Tour of Historic Homes and Gardens. (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - La Societe des 40 Hommes et 8 Chevaux, Richmond, Voiture 449, stationary with note on back. (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - The Quarters, Fredericksburg, Virginia. (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - The Romance of Iron and Steel in America: Old Dominion Iron & Steel Works, Inc. (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities membership card for Mrs. A. J. Montague. (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Order form for Chestnut Farms Dairy. (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Envelope for the Home for Confederate Women. (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Lens cleaner from the S. Galeski Optical Company. (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Business card of G. B. Jones. (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Blank check from the Citizens National Bank, Orange, Virginia. (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - List of the members of the House of Delegates and their post office, city or county residence, telegraph office, and express office. (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Charter and By-laws of Saint Andrew's Association. (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - Advertisement for W. J. Overcash, cabinet maker, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - Advertisement for Tidewater Tales by William C. Garnett. (Box 61, Folder 29)
  - Price list of drawn linen by Mrs. Evan Snead, Jr., Richmond, Virginia (2 copies). (Box 61, Folder 30)
  - Business card for H. Tyler Smith, traveling freight agent, Southern Railway. (Box 61, Folder 31)
  - Envelopes and stationary headed Executive Chamber. (Box 61, Folder 32)
  - Envelope addressed to Mr. Herbert W. Jackson President Virginia Trust Company (printed). (Box 61, Folder 33)
  - Advertisement for John L. Ratcliffe, florist. (Box 61, Folder 34)
  - Diet List for Hypertrophic Arthritis from Dr. Thomas F. Wheeldon, Richmond, Virginia. (Box 61, Folder 35)
  - Advertisement for Attilio Codognato, jeweller, Venice, Italy. (Box 61, Folder 36)
  - Invitation from Le Bureau de la Conférence Internationale de Droit Maritime.... (Box 61, Folder 37)
  - Adverisement for José Duarte Jorge de Jesus, antique shop, Lisbon, Portugal. (Box 61, Folder 38)
  - Jancourt's Railway and Steamship Tourist Map of Europe and Guide Book to Europe. (Box 61, Folder 39)
  - Gulf map from Washington D.C. to Virginia Beach, Virginia. (Box 61, Folder 40)
  - Advertisement for the Columbia Cafe, Washington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 41)
  - Advertisements for Arcade Sunshine Dry Cleaners, Washington D.C. (3 ads). (Box 61, Folder 42)
  - Notecards with the heading The Army and Navy Club Washington (5 cards). (Box 61, Folder 43)
  - Advertisement for Quality Floor and Painting Co., Inc., Capitol Heights, Maryland. (Box 61, Folder 44)
  - Advertisement for Central Auto Works, Washington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 45)
  - Advertisement for the Tolman Laundry and Dry Cleaning, WAshington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 46)
  - Advertisement for a lecture at Castelberg's jewellers. (Box 61, Folder 47)
  - Petition from the Massachusetts congressional delegation to the president for application of the Boynton Single Rail Patents and System to U.S. railroads. (Box 61, Folder 48)
  - Advertisement for Capitol Mirror Co., Washington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 49)
  - Advertisement for the Willard Roof restaurant, Washington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 50)
  - Advertisement for Spee Dee Kleen safe non-explosive dry cleaner. (Box 61, Folder 51)
  - Charlie Coulson the Drummer Boy: A True Story of the American War by M. L. Rossvally. (Box 61, Folder 52)
  - Advertisement for Alnwick bedspreads, Poughkeepsie, New York. (Box 61, Folder 53)
  - Advertisement for the Duplicating Letter Company, Washington D.C. (Box 61, Folder 54)
  - United States Customs Tariff, Hudson Forwarding & Shipping Co. (Box 61, Folder 55)
  - Invitation from the Nineteenth of April Committee of Concord, Massachusetts. (Box 61, Folder 56)
  - Brochure for the Cripple Creek Short Line Railroad trip. (Box 61, Folder 57)
  - The Annapolis Tea Burning and Dr. Charles Alexander Warfield. (Box 61, Folder 58)
  - The Wastes of Monopoly, tearsheet from Collier's. (Box 61, Folder 59)
  - Trusts, the Export Trade, and the New Party by Louis D. Brandeis, tearsheet from Collier's. (Box 61, Folder 60)
  - Trusts, Efficiency, and the New Party by Louis D. Brandeis, tearsheet from Collier's. (Box 61, Folder 61)
  - Envelope printed for A. J. Montague as congressman. (Box 61, Folder 62)
  - The Men at Armageddon by Richard Harding Davis, tearsheet from Collier's. (Box 61, Folder 63)
  - Business card for G. W. Bunting, Ltd., bootmakers, London, England. (Box 61, Folder 64)
  - Letterhead Democratic National Congressional Committee containing heading In This Land of the Free--Privilege and Monopoly Stand Behind a Tariff Wall. (Box 61, Folder 65)
  - Letterhead Democratic National Congressional Committee containing heading Why Are Farmers Misled as to Reciprocity with Canada?. (Box 61, Folder 66)
  - Work of the Democratic House of Representatives. (Box 61, Folder 67)
  - Labor and the Trusts, tearsheet from Collier's. (Box 61, Folder 68)
  - Envelope addressed Andrew J. Montague, Esq. (of Amerique). (Box 61, Folder 69)
  - Placecard for The Speaker. (Box 61, Folder 70)
  - Appointment reminder for Mrs. A. J. Montague with Dr. Walter P. Bronston, Podiatrist. (Box 61, Folder 71)
  - Envelope for A. J. Montague for mailing the Congressional Record. (Box 61, Folder 72)
  - Calling cards for individuals, A-D. (Box 61, Folder 73)
  - Calling cards for individuals, E-L. (Box 61, Folder 74)
  - Calling cards for individuals, M. (Box 61, Folder 75)
  - Calling cards for individuals, N-Z. (Box 61, Folder 76)
- XI: Scrapbooks, 1883-1916., Extent: 1 box. (Box 62)
  Scrapbooks, 1883-1916, contain clippings concerning Virginia and national politics and consisting mainly of newspaper clippings. Some topics are general assembly elections; the Danville riots; presidential campaigns; party platforms; tariffs; labor; wages; trusts; currency; Montague's gubernatorial campaign and his inauguration; the 1901-1902 state constitutional convention; Woodrow Wilson; Germany; Mexico; and World War I.
  - Scrapbook, 3 November 1883-1 February 1884, covering the General Assembly elections and the Danville riots. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 7 June-18 September 1888, covering the nominations of Grover Cleveland and Benjamin Harrison; party platforms on tariffs, labor, wages, trusts, etc. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 9-18 August 1896, covering the campaigns of William Jennings Bryan and William McKinley; the silver and gold standard controversy. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 3 November 1897-11 September 1901, covering Andrew Jackson Montague's election and term as Attorney-General and primary nomination as governor. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 22-29 August 1901, covering the state constitutional convention and the Republican gubernatorial nominating convention. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 16 September 1901-6 May 1902, covering Andrew Jackson Montague's nomination for governor, the election, and Montague's inauguration. (Box 62)
  - Scrapbook, 3 December 1915-9 September 1916, coverning President Woodrow Wilson, Mexico, and Germany. (Box 62)
- XII: Newspaper clippings, 1897-1938., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 63-65)
  Newspaper Clippings, 1897-1938, containing clippings covering Andrew Jackson Montague's political career and service as Attorney General, Governor, and Congressman. They also cover Virginia and national politics. Clippings also cover history, economics, and other topics.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1897. (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1899. (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1900. (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1901. (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1902. (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1903. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1904, folder 1 of 3. (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 2 of 3. (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1904, folder 3 of 3. (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 1 of 5. (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 2 of 5. (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 3 of 5. (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 4 of 5. (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1905, folder 5 of 5. (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1906. (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1907. (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1908. (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1909. (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1910. (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1911, folder 1 of 3. (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1911, folder 2 of 3. (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1911, folder 3 of 3. (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1912. (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1913. (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1914. (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1915. (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1916. (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1917. (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1918. (Box 64, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1920. (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1924. (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1925. (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1927. (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1928. (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1929. (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1930. (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1931. (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1932. (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1933. (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1934. (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1936. (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1938. (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 1 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 2 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 3 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 4 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 5 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings, no date, folder 6 of 6. (Box 65, Folder 19)
- Oversize materials., Extent: 2 boxes. (Box 66-67)
  Contains oversize materials belonging to the collection. Collection contains placeholders for this material within the regular folders.